# Andrew (Howon) Kim

# Software Engineer

Austintown, OH howonkim@berkeley.edu 408-628-2000

I have diverse experience, ranging from building a startup from its inception to scaling it up and working in prominent companies. I am a passionate and dedicated professional with a strong focus on data analysis and artificial intelligence. In my first six months at LG and GM, I greatly achieved the first prize in a worldwide data analysis competition and also received Golden Awards for my contributions to smart factory initiatives. My commitment to excellence and innovation drives my success in delivering impactful results.

## **Experience**

**Ultium Cells LLC** • Company of General Motors and LG Energy Solution

Computer Vision Engineer • Lordstown, OH

04/2023 - Present

- Developed statistical models using terabytes of manufacturing data and deep learning algorithms to detect defects.
- Experienced with various camera systems and optical techniques, including Keyence, Cognex, and Basler.
- Proficient in Python, C++, and WPF, delivering high-quality software solutions.
- Awarded 1st Prize in a Global Data Analysis Competition by LG Energy Solution.
- Redesigned traditional manufacturing UI into a breakthrough interface, unprecedented in the industry.
- Possess a systematic understanding of advanced manufacturing systems, including PLC, SPC, and MES.
- Working at HQ since August 2023; served as a partner employee from April 2023 to August 2023.

#### **ReviewMe** • eBook Review Platform Using Machine Learning

Software Engineer • Seoul, Korea

09/2020 - 12/2021

- Researched deep learning model to evaluate concentration level with facial components for review system.
- Analyzed brain waves and facial components.
- Swift, SwiftUI, MLKit, ARKit, and Vision Framework.
- Patent for Kindle like review system and AI funds granted from government.

#### Samsung Electronics • Android Framework Department

Software Engineer • Suwon, Korea

06/2020 - 08/2020

- Researched machine learning project to automatically sort notifications in situational importance.
- Analyzed and optimized the Samsung frameworks written in Kotlin and Java.
- Experienced in Git, documentation, agile development, and led weekly intern sprint planning session.

#### **AltoyGames** • Game Studio Startup

Software Engineer and Founder • Suwon, Korea

01/2020 - 06/2020

• Game development in Unity 3D and C#. Developed core components and algorithms from 2D to VR styled games.

### **Education**

#### University of California, Berkeley • Data Science • Berkeley, CA

12/2022

- Studied Computer Science and Data Science and graduated as Data Science: Applied Mathematics and Modeling.
- Data, Inference, and Decisions, Artificial Intelligence, Database Systems, Linear Programming and Network Flows, Nonlinear and Discrete Optimization.